{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pepperpot","incorrectAnswers":["Plov","Cou Cou and Flying Fish","Shawarma"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Guyana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Azerbaijan","incorrectAnswers":["Georgia","Syria","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Iran?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Guam","incorrectAnswers":["Saipan","Puerto Rico","Republic of Palau"],"question":"What is the largest of the Mariana Islands, a U.S. territory located in the western Pacific Ocean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Superstar","incorrectAnswers":["Black Hole Sun","Poor Poor Pitiful Me","Nobody's Fault But Mine"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by Rita Coolidge and was later covered by Sonic Youth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"David","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel","John","Michael"],"question":"Who killed Goliath?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malawi","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","France","Mauritius"],"question":"Lilongwe is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maputo","incorrectAnswers":["Managua","Libreville","Manama"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mozambique?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Kaiser Chiefs","Jethro Tull"],"question":"Who Had A Hit In 1996 With \"Don't Look Back In Anger\"","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"James Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Marvin Gaye","Luther Vandross","Prince"],"question":"With Which Singer Is \"Get Up I Feel Like A Sex Machine\" Associated? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Nintendo Entertainment System","incorrectAnswers":["Natural Emitting Screen","Near Energy Source","Nebulous Endocrine Station"],"question":"What does the acronym \"NES\" stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the study and interpretation of symbols, or a set of symbols","incorrectAnswers":["the structure of cells","the process of biological evolution","reptiles and amphibians"],"question":"What is Symbology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dan Aykroyd","incorrectAnswers":["Danny Glover","Danny Trejo","Dustin Hoffman"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Nanny and Ghostbusters?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Hot Spice ","incorrectAnswers":["Strong Taste","Lazy Cooking","Secret Flavour"],"question":"What does 'Garam Masala' mean in Hindi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michelangelo","incorrectAnswers":["Vincent van Gogh","Caravaggio","Georges Seurat"],"question":"Which artist painted the Sistine Chapel ceiling?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Stockholm","incorrectAnswers":["Monrovia","Helsinki","Oslo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Sweden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"parasitic worms","incorrectAnswers":["plankton","primates","animal behaviour"],"question":"What is Helminthology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jacqueline Bisset","incorrectAnswers":["Sophia Loren","Mila Kunis","Hilary Duff"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including Murder on the Orient Express and Counterpart?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The synthesis of non-terrestial life ","incorrectAnswers":["People from different continents","Refugees","Life in extremely cold climates"],"question":"What is Xenobiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Deer Hunter","incorrectAnswers":["Platoon","Full Metal Jacket","Apocalypse Now"],"question":"Which Vietnam War film features Robert De Niro, John Savage and Christopher Walken as the hunted?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Radiation poisoning","incorrectAnswers":["Drowning","She was hit by a car","She was struck by lightning"],"question":"What did Marie Curie die of on 4th July, 1934?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Decagon","incorrectAnswers":["Octagon","Hexagon","Triangle"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with ten sides?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Israel","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","Qatar","Iran"],"question":"Haifa is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"30 Years","incorrectAnswers":["34 Years","20 Years","18 Months"],"question":"For how long did the 30 Years War last?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Whiskey","incorrectAnswers":["Wizard","Warlock","Womble"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter W?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"medicine relating to women, or of women in general","incorrectAnswers":["prehistoric climates","the effect of evolution on ethology","fungus + -ology, see mycology"],"question":"What is Gynaecology or Gynecology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Prokofiev","incorrectAnswers":["Beethoven","Strauss","Stravinsky"],"question":"Who composed the ballet \"Romeo & Juliet\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"R.E.M.","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American alternative rock band released the album 'Automatic for the People'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Althea Gibson","incorrectAnswers":["Venus Williams","Serena Williams","Maureen Dalyweather"],"question":"Who was the first African-American female to win a Wimbledon Tennis event?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"2","incorrectAnswers":["1/2","4","8"],"question":"How Many Crotchets Do You Get In A Minim?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Syria","Cyprus","Lebanon"],"question":"Ankara is the capital of ______?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Azerbaijan","Pakistan","Kazakhstan"],"question":"Lviv is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Fantasia","Elatia","Bodhi"],"question":"Which of these is a state of enlightenment in Buddhism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Joni Mitchell","incorrectAnswers":["Carole King","Janis Joplin","Stevie Nicks"],"question":"Which music icon is famous for songs like \"Both Sides Now\" and \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Letterbox","incorrectAnswers":["Fullscreen","High Dynamic Range","Pan and Scan"],"question":"What is the name of the format used for presenting wide theatrical images on TV while maintaining their original aspect ratio?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VII","incorrectAnswers":["George IV","George V","William I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1485-1509?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Calvin Coolidge","incorrectAnswers":["Calvin Reagan","Calvin Nixon","Calvin Benington"],"question":"Which US President had the first name 'Calvin'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Baghdad","incorrectAnswers":["Belgrade","Dushanbe","Kabul"],"question":"What is the capital city of Iraq?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kathy Bates","incorrectAnswers":["Anjelica Huston","Julia Roberts","Meryl Streep"],"question":"Who won the 1990 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Annie Wilkes in Misery?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nine horizontal stripes of blue and white, with a blue square in the top left containing a white cross.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with a white crescent moon and star.","Three equal horizontal bands of white, blue, and red","Red with five yellow stars in the top left."],"question":"What does the flag of Greece look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Volkswagen","incorrectAnswers":["Renault","Audi","Toyota"],"question":"The Polo is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Catch-22","incorrectAnswers":["Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man","The Stranger","To Kill A Mockingbird"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Yossarian'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Wise Blood","incorrectAnswers":["Tinker","On the Road","Portnoy's Complaint"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Hazel Motes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Return of the King'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Within Temptation","incorrectAnswers":["Luv'","The Cats","2 Unlimited"],"question":"Which Dutch metal band released the studio album 'The Heart of Everything'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Francis Ford Coppola","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Godfather Part II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"United States","incorrectAnswers":["Brunei","Bahrain","Vietnam"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Mac 'N' Cheese?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After two male musicians witness a murder, they flee in an all-female band disguised as women.","incorrectAnswers":["A high school student is sent thirty years into the past in a time-traveling car.","A freed slave sets out to rescue his wife from a brutal plantation-owner.","A girl with her own sense of justice decides to help those around her and discovers love."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Some Like It Hot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The fiddle","incorrectAnswers":["The piano","The guitar","The trumpet"],"question":"What folksy state instrument of Missouri often accompanies the state folk dance, the square dance?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1773","incorrectAnswers":["1812","1861","1914"],"question":"In what year did the Sons of Liberty throw a tea party in Boston?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Glen Miller","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Acres","Laurence Ransom","Mark Bosworth"],"question":"Name The Musical Major Whose Plane Dissapeared Somewhere Over The English Channel In December 1944","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"New York City","incorrectAnswers":["Miami","Liverpool","Southampton"],"question":"What had been the planned destination of the Titanic before it sank?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Loitering","incorrectAnswers":["Shoplifting","Jaywalking","Vandalism"],"question":"What crime could be considered if someone is hanging out in public for no good reason?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jack","incorrectAnswers":["Mike","Chuck","Rob"],"question":"Which Boys Name Is Also The Name Of The Object Ball In Bowls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lead & Tin","incorrectAnswers":["Copper & Iron","Copper & Lead","Iron & Tin"],"question":"What Is The Alloy Pewter Made From","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Braveheart","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo 13","Babe","The Postman (Il Postino)"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1995?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"American Elm","incorrectAnswers":["American Redbud","American Willow","American Tree"],"question":"What is the common name for the tree species Ulmus americana?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Katharine Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Glenn Close","Vivien Leigh","Angela Lansbury"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Rose Sayer in The African Queen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of East Timor is on which continent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"DVD","incorrectAnswers":["Blu-ray","Floppy Disk","VHS"],"question":"What type of media was first released in 1996?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jill","incorrectAnswers":["A Bitch","A Lioness","A Queen"],"question":"What is the word for a female wombat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Iron Maiden","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Squeeze"],"question":"Which English heavy metal band released the song 'Hallowed Be Thy Name'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jane Austen","incorrectAnswers":["Emily Bronte","Oscar Wilde","John Updike"],"question":"Who wrote the novel \"Emma\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pangaea","incorrectAnswers":["Laurasia","Rodinia","Gondwana"],"question":"What name is given to the single super-continent that existed 200 million years ago?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovenia","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Samoa","Montenegro"],"question":"Ljubljana is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Giorgio Armani","incorrectAnswers":["Lacoste","Tripadvisor","Bacardi"],"question":"Which of these brands has a eagle on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Northern Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","New Zealand","Vietnam"],"question":"In which country would you find the Giant's Causeway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Terry Pratchett","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Isaac Asimov","Brandon Sanderson"],"question":"Which author penned the Discworld Series of sci-fi novels?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gilbert Stuart","incorrectAnswers":["Edward Mitchell Bannister","Hannah Robinson","Ralph Earl"],"question":"Which Rhode Islander painted portraits of the first 6 presidents of the USA?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"E-Type","incorrectAnswers":["T14","Astra","Model 3"],"question":"Which of these was a model of car made by Jaguar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ear","incorrectAnswers":["Nose","Hand","Foot"],"question":"Where in the body is the smallest human muscle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Fe","incorrectAnswers":["Az","Ri","Ir"],"question":"What is the symbol for Iron?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Connelly","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Weisz","Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which acress has starred in both A Beautiful Mind and Requiem for a Dream?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Uganda","Zambia","Kenya"],"question":"Which country did Idi Amin invade in 1979?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Clive Sinclair","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Berners-Lee","Casio Bernadelli","Marcus Holding"],"question":"Who Invented the worlds first electronic pocket calculator in 1972?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tripadvisor","incorrectAnswers":["Swarovski","Abercrombie & Fitch","Twitter"],"question":"Which of these brands has a owl on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Karma","incorrectAnswers":["Hajj","Salat","Zakat"],"question":"Which of the following is not a pillar of Islam?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"They get turned into bricks","incorrectAnswers":["They die","They become mind controlled","They fall into an endless slumber"],"question":"In the Mario games, what happens to the residents of the Mushroom Kingdom when Bowser takes over?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Hey Ya!\" by Outkast","incorrectAnswers":["\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"Pepper\" by Butthole Surfers"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"My baby don't mess around because she loves me so, and this I know for sure.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Himalayas","incorrectAnswers":["Aravalli","Vindhyas","Satpura"],"question":"Which is the largest mountain range in India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a white crescent moon and star.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal horizontal bands of red white and green.","Red with five yellow stars in the top left.","Red with a yellow sun having eight broadening rays extending to the edges."],"question":"What does the flag of Turkey look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hoover","incorrectAnswers":["Franklin","Roosevelt","Johnson"],"question":"U.S. President, Herbert C. _________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sun Tzu","incorrectAnswers":["Seneca","Aristotle","Pythagoras"],"question":"Who is known for writing \"The Art of War\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'St. Anger'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Animals'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Denmark","Puerto Rico"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Two equal horizontal bands of blue and yellow.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Huit","incorrectAnswers":["Otto","Acht","Six"],"question":"What is the French word for 'eight'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Liam Neeson","incorrectAnswers":["Ewan McGregor","Harrison Ford","Mark Hamill"],"question":"Who played the character Qui-Gon Jinn in the Star Wars movie \"The Phantom Menace\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Dravidian","Sino-Tibetan","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'Polish' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Belong Anywhere","incorrectAnswers":["Let your fingers do the walking","When you care enough to send the very best","Gotta catch 'em all!"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Airbnb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Virtual Reality","incorrectAnswers":["Augmented Reality","Visual Hologram","Immersive Space"],"question":"What 2 Word Term Is Given To A Simulated 3D Environment Used in Computer Graphics? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Butterflying","incorrectAnswers":["Basting","Marinating","Julienning"],"question":"What is the name for the preparation of meat for grilling by splitting it down the middle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince","New Moon","The Alchemist"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Harry Potter was a highly unusual boy in many ways.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Velociraptor","incorrectAnswers":["Tyrannosaurus Rex","Diplodocus","Stegosaurus"],"question":"Featured In The Film Jurassic Park, Which Creature's Name Means 'Quick Plunderer'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Russian Revolution","incorrectAnswers":["The Death of Stalin","The Collapse of the USSR","The Formation of the Cyrilic Alphabet"],"question":"What Major Event Occured In Russia In 1917?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Piglet","incorrectAnswers":["A Maggot","A Cygnet","A Colt"],"question":"What is the word for a young pig?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Heart of Darkness","incorrectAnswers":["The Quiet American","The Trial","Pale Fire"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Kurtz'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Broccoli ","incorrectAnswers":["Carrots","Spinach","Cabbage"],"question":"Which vegetable did President George Bush senior declare publicly that he did not like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Earth","incorrectAnswers":["Rocks","Pollen","Gemstones"],"question":"What is Geology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},